Long before the birth of light
there was darkness,
and from that darkness
came the Dark Elves.
Millennia ago the most ruthless
of their kind, Malekith,
sought to transform our universe
back into one of eternal night.
Such evil was possible through
the power of the Aether,
an ancient force of infinite destruction.
Malekith, the Asgardians attack.
The noble of armies of Asgard,
led by my father, King Bor,
waged a mighty war
against these creatures.
Bring in the Kursed.
As the nine worlds
converged above him
Malekith could at last
unleash the Aether.
But Asgard ripped
the weapon from his grasp.
Without it the Dark Elves fell.
With the battle all but lost
Malekith sacrificed his own people
in desperate attempt to
lay waste to Asgard's army.
Through their sacrifice we will survive.
It will not be in vain.
Malekith was vanquished
and the Aether was no more.
Or so we were led to believe...
Sire, the Aether,
shall we destroy it?
If only we could, but
its power is too great.
Bury it deep. Somewhere
no one will ever find it.
THOR: THE DARK WORLD
Subtitles by Bambula
Loki.
- Hello, mother.
Have I made you proud?
Please, don't make this worse.
Define worse.
- Enough!
I will speak to the prisoner alone.
I really don't see what
all the fuss is about.
Do you not truly feel the
gravity of your crimes?
Wherever you go there
is war, ruin and death.
I went down to Midgard to rule the
people of Earth as a benevolent God,
just like you.
We are not Gods. We are born, we
live, we die, just as humans do.
Give or take five thousand years.
All this because
Loki desires a throne.
It's my birthright!
Your birthright was
to die... as a child!
Cast out onto a frozen rock.
If I had not taken you in you
would not be here now to hate me.
If I am for the axe then for
mercy's sake just... swing it!
It's not that I don't love
our little talks, it's just...
I don't love them.
Frigga is the only reason you are still
alive and you will never see her again.
You'll spend the rest of
your days in the dungeon.
And what of Thor?
You'll make that witless oaf
king while I rot in chains?
Thor must strive to undo
the damage you have done,
he will bring order to
the Nine Realms and then,
yes, he will be king.
VANAHEIM
I've got this
completely under control!
Is that why everything is on fire?
You're welcome!
All yours.
Kronan! Kronan! Kronan!
Hello.
I accept your surrender.
Anyone else?
Perhaps next time we should
start with the big one.
Where do we go next? - Hogun, the peace
is nearly won across the Nine Realms.
You should stay here and be with
your people where your heart is.
Asgard can wait.
You have my thanks.
- As you have mine.
Heimdall, when you're ready.
ASGARD
Is Vanaheim secure?
- As Nornheim and Ria,
though our work would have gone
more quickly with you in form.
You must think I'm a piece of bread
that needs to be buttered so heavily.
That was not my intent.
The first time since Bifrost was destroyed,
the Nine Realms are in peace.
They're well reminded of our strength,
and you have earned their
respect and my gratitude.
Thank you.
Nothing out of order except your
confused and distracted heart.
This isn't about Jane Foster, father.
Human lives are fleeting, they're nothing.
You'd be better served by
what lies in front of you.
I'm telling you this not as the
All-Father, but as your father.
You are ready, the time has
come for you to take the throne.
Embrace it, celebrate what you
have won. Join your warriors.
Eat and drink, revel
in their celebration.
At least pretend to enjoy yourself.
Another!
There was a time you
would celebrate for weeks.
I remember you celebrated
the battle of Haragon
so much that you
nearly started a second.
Well, the first was so much fun.
Take a drink with me.
Surely the All-Father could have
no further task for you tonight.
No, this is one I set myself.
It does not go unnoticed
that you disappear each night.
There are Nine Realms.
Future king of Asgard
must focus on more than one.
I thank you for your sword and
for your counsel, good Lady Sif.
LONDON
Hi.
- Hi.
So, what's the story with you?
Why does there have to be a story,
there's no story.
You've spent the first ten minutes
of our date hiding behind a menu
that has three choices on it. It's
either chicken, vegetarian or fish, Jane.
I think there's a story
and I'm thinking the story
involves a guy?
It's complicated.
Is he still around?
- No, he...
went away.
- I've been there.
The going away, it's hard.
I'd been seeing a woman and
uh... she took a job in New York.
Eventually the distance killed it.
And... and the fact that she uh...
she kept sleeping with other dudes.
No.
- Oh, so many.
Hi. Could we get some wine please?
Sure, I'd love some.
- Richard, this is Darcy.
What are you doing here?
Hello.
- Sup?
So, I show up to work at the
lab-slash-your mom's house,
fully expecting you
to be moping around
in your pajamas eating ice cream
obsessing about you know who...
But you're not! You're
wearing lady clothes,
you even showered, didn't you?
You smell good.
Is there a point to all this, cause there
really has to be a point to all this.
Right. You know that scientific
equipment you don't look at anymore?
You might wanna start
looking at it again.
This is the reason we
came all the way out here.
It's malfunctioning.
- That's what I said.
That's what I did! But you just
did it a little more scientific.
- I'm sure it's nothing. - Yeah.
It doesn't look like nothing.
It kind-a looks like the
readings Erik was rumbling about.
Our friend Eric, kind
of went... banana balls.
He is not interested. - I am interested.
- I am not interested. Time to go now.
Okay.
Short but sweet.
- She needs help.
I think I'm gonna have sea-bass.
- Sea bass. Yeah, sea bass is good.
Sea bass, sea bass, sea bass, sea bass, sea
bass, sea bass, sea bass... sea bass.
Sea bass...
Jane, maybe you should stop saying
sea bass and go out to your friend.
This was so fun.
You know, I'll just stay
here and say sea bass alone.
And I hate you.
- What? I said he was cute.
Just shut up and drive.
Here it says the next left.
Who is he?
- He's my intern.
You have an intern?
- Yeah.
Hello, Dr. Foster. It's uh... it's
a great honor to be working with you.
Right. I have to call Erik.
Oh, uh... take a right.
Left.
I have totally mastered driving in London.
Hi, Erik, it's me, again. Where are you?
I came here because you said you
were onto something and then vanished.
I'm here at Stonehenge,
for what has been an interesting
unfolding of events today.
The police were called to the scene
shortly after 11 a. m. this morning,
after a seemingly harmless
rambler approached the area,
then decided to strip naked and
effectively
terrorize tourists there
with scientific equipment
while shouting that he
was trying to save them.
The man later identified as noted
Astrophysicist Dr. Erik Selvig
has been called in for
questioning by police.
Come on! This is exciting!
Look! The intern is exciting!
- Ian.
Do you want the phase meter?
- No.
Bring the phase meter.
The toaster looking thing.
- I know what the phase meter is.
How do I change the
ring tone on this thing?
An Astrophysicist with three degrees
should be able to change her own ring tone.
Why are you calling me? - I didn't want to
shout. Intern, the entrance is this way.
Ian. My name is Ian.
I am not getting stabbed
in the name of science.
It's okay! We're Americans!
Is that supposed to
make them like us?
Make it go away...
- Shhh...
Oh, they're kids.
Are you the police?
No, we're scientists. Well, I am.
Thanks.
- We just found it.
Can you show us?
That doesn't seem right.
Where did it go?
That's... that's incredible.
What happened?
Sometimes they come back,
sometimes they don't.
I want to throw something.
Jane, give me your shoe.
I haven't seen readings like this since...
New Mexico?
Don't touch anything!
Give me your shoe.
Were those the car keys?
Darcy!
The Aether awakens us.
The Convergence returns.
You're late.
Merriment can sometimes be
a heavier burden than battle.
Then you're doing one of them incorrectly.
Perhaps.
How fare the stars?
- Still shining.
From here I can see Nine
Realms and ten trillion souls.
You recall what I told
you of the Convergence?
Yes, the alignment of the worlds.
It approaches, doesn't it?
The universe hasn't seen this
marvel since before my watch began.
Few can sense it,
even fewer can see it.
A world that's infected
can be dangerous.
It is truly beautiful.
I see nothing.
Or perhaps that is not
the beauty you seek.
How is she?
- She's quite clever, your mortal.
She doesn't know it yet, but she
studies the Convergence as well.
Even...
- What?
I can't see her.
Jane! Where the hell were you?
Tell me you didn't call the police!
- What was I supposed to do?
Not call the police! - I was freaking out.
- You call the cops they call the feds,
the next thing you know we have SHIELD
crawling all over area 51 in the place.
Jane. - We had a stable gravitational
anomaly, we had unheeded access.
Our only competition
was ten years old!
Jane, you were gone for five hours!
What?
That's weird.
Typical.
Jane.
Sorry. I just needed to
make sure you were real,
it's been a very strange day.
- Well, I am. Jane...
Where were you?!
- Where were you?
Heimdall could not see you.
- I was right here where you left me.
I was waiting and then I was crying
and then I went out looking for you.
You said you were coming back. - I know,
I know, but the Bifrost was destroyed.
The Nine Realms erupted into chaos.
Wars were raging,
Marauders were pillaging.
I had to put an end to the slaughter.
As excuses go, that's not terrible.
But I saw you on TV, you
were... you were in New York!
Jane, I fought to protect you from
the dangers of my world, but...
I was wrong, I was a fool.
I believe that fate
brought us together.
Jane, I don't know where you were
or what happened, but I do know this.
What?
I know...
- You do?
Do what?
- What?
Hey!
Is that you?
We're kinda of the middle of something.
- I am pretty sure we're getting arrested.
Hold that thought.
Look at you! Still all
muscly and everything.
How's space?
- Space is fine.
Excuse me?
- Are you Jane Foster? - Yes.
Do you know this man?
He's my intern.
My intern's intern.
This is private property
and you're trespassing,
the lot of you.
You'll have to come with me.
Jane. Jane?
- Thor...
You alright?
- What just happened?
Place your hands on your head,
step back!
The woman is unwell.
- She's dangerous.
So am I.
Requesting armed response
officers to the scene.
Hold on to me.
- What are you doing?
Holy shit!
We have to do that again.
Hi.
Welcome to Asgard.
SVARTALHEIM
Look my legacy, Algrim.
I barely remember
the time before light.
Our survival will be your legacy.
Asgardians will suffer
as we have suffered.
I'll reclaim the Aether.
I'll restore our world and I'll
put an end to this poisonous world.
What's that?
- Be still.
This is not of Earth.
What is it?
We do not know. But she will not survive
the amount of energy surging within her.
That's a quantum field
generator, isn't it?
It's a Soul Forge.
Does a Soul Forge transfer
molecular energy from one
place to another?
Yes.
- It's a quantum field generator.
My words are mere noises to you
that you ignore them completely?
She's ill.
- She is mortal.
Illness is their defining trait.
I brought here because we can help her.
- She does not belong here in Asgard
anymore than a goat
belongs at a banquet table.
Did he just...
Who do you think you are?
- I'm Odin. King of Asgard.
Protector of the Nine Realms.
Oh. Well, I'm...
- I know very well who you are, Jane Foster.
You told your father about me?
Something is within her, father.
Something I have not seen before...
Her world has its healers, they're
called doctors. Let them deal with it.
Guards, take her back to Midgard.
No! I would not...
...touch her.
Jane, are you alright?
That's impossible.
The infection, it's defending her.
No, it's defending itself.
Come with me.
There are relics that
predate the universe itself.
What lies within her
appears to be one of them.
The Nine Realms are not eternal.
They had a dawn as they will have a dusk.
But before that dawn the
dark forces, the Dark Elves,
reigned absolute and unchallenged.
Born of eternal night, the Dark
Elves come to steal away the light.
There were these stories
mother told to us as children.
Their leader, Malekith made
a weapon out of that darkness,
it was called the Aether.
While the other relics
often appear as stones,
the Aether is fluid and ever changing.
It changes matter into dark matter
and seeks out to host bodies, drawing
strength from their life force.
Malekith sought to
use the Aether's power
to return the universe
to one of darkness.
But after eternities of bloodshed,
my father Bor, finally triumphed,
ushering in the peace that
lasted thousands of years.
What happened?
He killed them all.
Are you certain?
The Aether was said to have been
destroyed with them and yet here it is.
The Dark Elves are dead.
Does your book happen to
mention how to get it out of me?
No, it does not.
The Realms will be aligned soon.
You'll be the last of the Kursed.
- Let my life be sacrificed.
The same thing did our people.
You will become darkness,
doomed to this existence
until it consumes you.
And then no power of our
enemies won't stop me.
I'll destroy their defense
and resurrect the universe.
Odin continues to
bring me new friends.
How thoughtful.
The books I sent,
do they not interest you?
Is that how I'm to while
away eternity, reading?
I've done everything in my power to
make you comfortable, Loki. - Have you?
Does Odin share your concern?
Does Thor?
It must be so inconvenient them
asking after me day and night.
You know full well that your
actions have brought you here.
My actions?
I was merely giving truth to the lie
that I've been fed my entire life,
that I was born to be a king.
- A king?
A true king admits his faults.
What of the lives you took on Earth?
A mere handful compared to
the numbers Odin has taken himself.
Your father...
- He's not my father!
Then am I not your mother?
You're not.
Always so perceptive about
everyone but yourself.
When you came for me,
you knew I was in trouble.
Well, Heimdall had lost sight of
you, you were no longer on Earth.
Well, how's that possible?
- I believe you are and you weren't.
The Nine Realms travel within
Yggdrasil, orbiting Midgard
in much the way your
planet orbits the sun.
Every five thousand years
the worlds align perfectly.
We call this the Convergence.
During this time the borders
between worlds become blurred.
It's possible you found
one of these points.
We are lucky that it remained open.
Once the worlds pass out of
alignment,
the connection is lost.
I like the way you explain things.
What's gonna happen to me?
- I'll find a way to save you, Jane.
Your father said there was...
- My father doesn't know everything.
Don't let him hear you say that.
Jane Foster, please meet Frigga,
the Queen of Asgard, my mother.
Hi.
You might want to take
the stairs to the left.
The prisons. - Loki.
- Go, I will look after her.
It's as if they resent
being imprisoned.
There is no pleasing some creatures.
Return to your cells and no further
harm will come to you. You have my word.
Very well, you don't have my word.
Send a squadron to the weapons
vault, defend it at all costs.
Secure the dungeon.
- Odin.
Frigga. Go!
It's a skirmish, nothing to fear.
You've never been a very good liar.
Take her to you chambers, I'll come
for you when it's safe. - You take care.
Despite all I have survived,
my queen still worries over me.
It's only because I worry over
you that you have survived.
Listen to me now.
I need you to do everything I
ask and no questions. - Yes, ma'am.
Frigga.
Stand down, creature.
You may still survive this.
- I have survived worse, woman.
Who are you?
- I am Malekith,
and I would have what it is mine.
You have taken something, child.
Give it back.
Witch!
Where is the Aether?
- I'll never tell you.
I believe you.
The universe rotates on a
five thousand year cycle,
and once its cycled all the worlds align.
Imagine... imagine that this
is our world, and... and...
Thank you. And this is another
world. Normally they're separate,
but during the alignment
everything is connected.
All Nine Realms, all Nine Realms
are passing through each other.
And gravity, light, and even matter,
is crushing from one world to the other.
But if this happens to us now,
the result would be cataclysmic.
My gravimetric spikes can stabilize
the focal point of the Convergence.
This time the alignment,
and all the other worlds,
would just pass us by.
It's beautiful.
It's simple. Any questions?
Yeah. Can I have my shoe back?
I need your strength
to reclaim the Aether.
And when you wake up,
you will kill them all.
Jane Foster.
You need to come with us.
We are still unable to
restore the palace shields.
Our artillery cannot detect them,
even Heimdall cannot see them.
My King, we are all but defenseless.
She's your prisoner now?
Leave us.
I do not wish to fight with you.
Nor I with you,
but I intend to pursue Malekith.
- We possess the Aether,
Malekith will come to us.
- Yes, and you will destroy us.
You overestimate the
power of these creatures.
No, I value our people's lives.
I'll take Jane to the Dark World
and draw the enemy away from Asgard.
When Malekith pulls
the Aether from Jane,
it will be exposed vulnerable,
and I will destroy it and him.
If you fail,
you risk this weapon falling
into the hands of our enemies.
The risk is far greater
if we do nothing.
His ship could be over our heads
right now and we'd never even know it.
If and when he comes, his men will
fall by ten thousand Asgardian blades.
And how of our men shall fall on theirs?
- As many as are needed!
We will fight!
Until the last Asgardian breath,
the last drop of Asgardian blood.
And how are you
different from Malekith?
The difference,
my son, is that I will win.
Jane isn't called me back.
Erik isn't calling me back.
Stupid SHIELD isn't calling me back!
What is SHIELD?
- It's a secret.
Hey, Erik. It's Darcy again.
Thor came back.
He took Jane to Asgard.
And um... I'm not sure
what I'm supposed to do.
Something else went missing this week
when Astrophysicist, Dr. Erik Selvig,
notable for his involvement in
the Alien invasion of New York
streaked nude across Stonehenge.
- Darcy, you really need to look at this.
Your friend Erik, what
was his last name again?
...disrobed and began shouting at
visitors at the historic site.
He was later taken into police
custody for psychiatric evaluation.
The police are still
refusing to confirm...
You're not in Odin's war council?
The Bifrost is closed
by your father's orders.
No one is to come or to go.
We face an enemy that
is invisible even to me.
Of what use is a guardian such as that?
Malekith will return, you know this.
I'll need your help.
I cannot overrule my King's wishes,
not even for you.
- I'm not asking you to.
The Realms need the All-Father strong
and unchallenged,
whether he is or not.
But he is blinded, Heimdall,
by hatred and by grief.
- As are we all.
I see clearly enough.
The risks are too great.
Everything that we do from here on
is a risk,
there is no other way.
What do you require of me?
What I'm about to ask of you
is treason of the highest order.
Success will bring us exile and
failure shall mean our death.
Malekith knew the Aether was here.
He can sense its power.
If we do nothing he
will come for it again,
but this time lay
waste to all of Asgard.
We must move Jane off world.
The Bifrost has been shut down and
the Tesseract locked away in a vault.
There are other paths off Asgard,
ways known only to a few.
- One, actually.
No.
Thor.
After all this time now
you come to visit me.
Why?
Have you come to gloat?
To mock?
- Loki, enough.
No more illusions.
Now you see me, brother.
Did she suffer?
I did not come here to share our grief.
Instead I offer you the chance
of a far richer sacrament.
Go on. - I know you seek
vengeance as much as I do.
You help me escape Asgard and I
will grant it to you, vengeance.
And afterwards, this cell.
You must be truly desperate
to come to me for help.
What makes you think you can trust me?
- I don't.
Mother did.
You should know that when we
fought each other in the past,
I did so with the glimmer of hope that
my brother was still in there somewhere.
That hope no longer
exists to protect you.
You betray me and I will kill you.
When do we start?
He will betray you.
- He will try.
This is so unlike you, brother.
So clandestine.
Are you sure you wouldn't
rather just punch your way out?
If you keep speaking I just might.
Fine. As you wish. I'm not even here.
Is this better?
- It's better company at least.
Still, we could be less conspicuous.
Hm, brother. You look ravishing.
It will hurt no less when
I kill you in this form.
Very well. Perhaps you prefer
one of your new companions,
given that you seem
to like them so much.
Oh, this is much better.
Costume's a bit much... so tight.
But the confidence,
I can feel the righteousness surging.
Hey, you wanna have a rousing
discussion about truth,
honor, patriotism?
God bless America...
What?
You can at least
furnish me with a weapon.
My dagger, something!
At last, a little common sense.
I thought you liked tricks.
What then? Your lovely mortal is being
guarded by a legion of our Einherjar
who will see you coming from miles away.
- I won't be the one who comes for her.
I'm not hungry.
Good, let's go.
You? - I'm Loki. You may have heard
of me. - That was for New York.
I like her.
- And what of the All-Father?
It is my sworn duty to notify him
of crimes against the throne.
You called me here on an urgent matter.
What is it?
- Treason, my lord. - Whose?
Mine.
My King, the mortal has been taken.
Stop Thor, by any means necessary.
Here they are. Take them.
On my command.
I'll hold them off.
Take her.
Thank you.
Betray him and I'll kill you.
It's good to see you too, Sif.
Assuming you can get Loki's help,
and you can free this mortal,
what good would it do? We'd all be dead
the minute we step one
foot outside the palace.
That, my friend, is where
we won't be leaving by foot.
I will give you as much time as I can.
Thank you, my friend.
If you even think about betraying him...
You'll kill me? Evidently
there will be a line.
I thought you said you
knew how to fly this thing.
I said how hard could it be.
They're on the ship!
Get to the ship!
Well, whatever you're doing,
brother, I suggest you do it faster.
Shut up, Loki.
You must have missed something. - I didn't,
I'm pressing every button on this thing.
No, don't hit it, just press it gently.
I am pressing it gently. It's not working!
I think you missed a column.
- Shut up!
Look, why don't you let me take
over, I'm clearly the best pilot.
Is that right? Well, out of the two
of us which one can actually fly?
Oh, dear. Is she dead?
- Jane?
I am okay.
Not a word.
Now they're following us.
Now they're firing at us! - Yeah,
thank you for the commentary, Loki!
It's not at all distracting!
Well done, you just
decapitated your grandfather.
You know this is wonderful.
This is a tremendous idea.
Let's steal the biggest and
most obvious ship in the universe
and escape in that,
flying around the city, smashing into
everything in sight so everyone can see us.
It's brilliant, Thor! It's truly brilliant!
I see your time in the dungeons
has made you no less graceful, Loki.
You lied to me.
I'm impressed.
- I'm glad you're pleased.
Now, do as you promised.
Take us to your secret pathway.
Frandal.
- Right.
For Asgard.
Nothing personal, boys.
Loki.
- If it were easy everyone would do it.
Are you mad?
- Possibly.
We must attack now.
No.
Asgard is not important anymore.
The Aether has returned home.
What I could do with the power
that flows through those veins.
It would consume you.
- She's holding up alright,
for now. - She's strong in ways
you'd never even know.
Say goodbye.
- Not this day.
This day, the next, a hundred
years is nothing. It's a heartbeat.
You'll never be ready.
The only woman whose love you prized
will be snatched from you.
- And will that satisfy you?
Satisfaction is not in my nature.
- Surrender is not in mine.
The son of Odin.
- No, not just of Odin!
You think you alone who loved mother?
You had her tricks, but I had her trust!
Trust. Was that her last expression?
Trust? When you let her die!
- What help were you in your cell?
Who put me there? Who put me there?!
- You know damn well!
You know damn well!
She wouldn't want us to fight.
Well, she wouldn't exactly be shocked.
I wish I could trust you.
Trust my rage.
You'll have to sign for your
father's belongings, Mr. Selvig.
What?
Oh, yeah. My father, Dr. Erik Selvig.
One; a man's leather wallet,
brown. One key ring with three keys.
Prescription medicine.
Various.
And... These.
- Yeah, those.
Thank goodness.
Eric.
Yes?
- It's uh... Darcy.
Darcy.
It's so good to see you.
- Uh... I missed you too.
How did you find me?
- You were naked on TV.
Okay, time to go. Lots to do.
Getting weird now.
I should not be left in
charge of stuff like this,
I don't get paid enough.
I don't get paid period.
I'm uh... Ian by the way.
Uh... Darcy's intern.
I don't get paid either.
Are you alright?
I have had a God in my
brain. I don't recommend it.
Dr. Selvig, your gear is beeping at me.
It's happening, sooner
than I calculated.
Wait, what's happening?
Birds? Birds are happening?
- Starlings, it's called a murmuration.
My dad used to take me
bird watching as a kid.
Eric?
- Look.
Where did they go?
What the hell was that?!
Why are you smiling?
There's nothing more reassuring
than realizing that the
world is crazier than you are.
Take me to Jane's lab!
Jane.
Malekith.
Alright, are you ready?
- I am.
You know this plan of yours is going
to get us killed. - Yeah, possibly.
You still don't trust me, brother?
- Would you?
No, I wouldn't.
Thor!
No!
You really think I cared
about Frigga,
about anybody?
All I ever wanted was you
and Odin dead at my feet!
Malekith!
I am Loki of Jotunheim
and I bring you a gift!
I ask only one thing in return,
a good seat from which
to watch Asgard burn.
He is an enemy of Asgard,
he was locked in a cell.
Look at me.
Loki, now!
No!
See you in hell, monster!
No, no, no!
Oh you fool, you didn't listen!
- I know,
I'm a fool. I'm a fool!
Stay with me. Stay!
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry...
It's alright. I'll tell
father what you did here today.
I didn't do it for him.
No!
He's gonna unleash it,
not just on Asgard or on a star,
Malekith is gonna destroy everything.
How? Jane, how?
I saw him on Earth. Why would
he go to Earth? - The Convergence.
Oh, God. None of this would have
happened if I hadn't found the Aether.
Then Malekith would have only
possessed it that much sooner.
I only found it because
I was looking for you. - Jane...
Now we're trapped here.
It's not me.
Hello?
- Hi, Jane, it's Richard.
Richard?! Where are you?
- I'm still in the office.
It's... It's been a crazy day here today.
- Oh, my God! This is amazing.
Is it? I quite enjoyed our lunch
despite never actually ordering anything.
How am I getting service here? - Is this
a bad time? Do you want me to try you later?
No, no, no, no! Please, whatever
you do, do not hang up the phone.
Okay then. I was just wondering
if you want to try again?
Uh... maybe dinner next time?
- Uh... yeah, yeah, yeah.
Um... just stay on the phone, okay?
- Yeah, I will.
Oh, my God.
Am I interrupting something?
- No, no, no, nothing at all.
Come on. - I'm losing you there, are
you in a tunnel? - Wait, where are we going?
Hello?
- Why are there so many shoes in here?
I'll just text her.
So who's Richard?
- Really?
Jane, you can't just leave like that.
The whole world is going crazy.
All the stuff we saw is spreading.
Did you go to a party?
- Eric?
Jane, how wonderful.
You've been to Asgard.
- Where are your pants?
He says it helps him think. - Okay. I'm gonna
need everything you got on this.
All the work you've been doing on
gravimetric anomalies, everything.
Okay.
- Are you well, Eric?
Your brother is not coming, is he?
- Loki is dead.
Thank God.
I... I'm so sorry.
- Thank you.
Forgive me, my liege.
I've returned from the
Dark World with news.
Thor?
- There's no sign of Thor,
nor the weapon, but...
What?
We've found the body.
Loki.
Malekith is going to fire the Aether at a
spot where all the 9 worlds are connected.
Amplifying the weapon's impact.
With each additional world,
the power will increase exponentially,
effect would be universal.
Yes, but the alignment
is only temporary.
He must be exactly at the
right place at the right time.
Well, how do we know where it is?
- We follow the directions.
This had happened before, thousands of
years ago. The Ancient were there to see it.
All the great constructions:
Mayas, the Chinese, the Egyptians,
they've used gravitational
effects of the Convergence.
They left us a map.
Stonehenge...
Snowdon, Great Orme.
These are all coordinates taking us...
here.
Greenwich. - The walls between
worlds will be almost nonexistent.
Physics is gonna go ballistic.
Increase and decrease in gravity,
spatial extrusions.
The very fabric of
reality is gonna be torn apart.
Better to get my pants.
Focus, this is important.
We'll hammer them in all over the site
and Jane and Eric will activate
them from the top of the tower.
They're taped together.
Do you even know what these things do?
No.
- Neither do I.
Come on, come on!
- Fine!
Holy shit!
You need not to come
so far, Asgardian!
Death will to come
to you soon enough.
Not by your hand!
Your world and your family
will be extinguished.
We're running out of time.
- Almost there.
Are you sure this is going to work?
These devices were made to detect anomalies,
not causing them.
- Come on.
Come on, Darcy.
You know with all that power,
I thought you would hit harder.
Done.
The Convergence will be in
full effect in 7 minutes.
That just means we'll have to
keep Malekith busy for eight.
Okay. You might wanna
hold on to something.
That is awesome.
How did you do that?
Well, gravitational fields interact
with weak spots between worlds
creating...
- Oh, there's a guy with a sword!
Oops.
- Let's go.
What the hell just happened?
Move!
What are you all doing?
You need to get out of here! Now!
You're joking, right?
That's Thor out there waving
his hammer around on everything.
Confirm the ship is hostile?
- Confirm, the ship is hostile.
You have permission to engage.
- Roger. The missiles locked.
The missile's on its way.
Missile off target! I repeat!
I'm losing control.
Mayday! Mayday!
What are you doing?
- My signal is not connected.
Jane! Come on!
Are you alright?
- You saved my life.
Yeah. Yes, I did.
Darcy?
- Jane!
Ian?
- Selvig?
Mjolnir!
How do I get to Greenwich?
- Take this train, three stops.
Sorry. Sorry.
We're out of time.
- Jane. Jane!
Thor!
You're too late.
The Convergence is on its peak.
Those things will stop him?
- Not from here?
We can't get close enough.
I can.
Malekith!
The darkness returns, Asgardian.
Have you come to witness
the end of your universe?
I've come to accept your surrender.
You think you can stop me?
The Aether cannot be destroyed.
But you can.
Thor! No!
Jane!
Everybody okay?
He's gonna come back.
Except, you know, last time
he was gone for like two years.
It's only been two days.
Did he say anything before he left?
Yeah, he had to figure some
stuff out with his father.
He kinda committed treason... on a way out.
You once said there would
never be wiser king than me.
You were wrong. The alignment has
brought all the realms together.
Every one of them saw you
offer your life to save them.
What can Asgard offer
its new King in return?
My life.
Father, I cannot be King of Asgard.
I will protect Asgard and all the
realms with my last and every breath,
but I cannot do so from that chair.
Loki for all his grave imbalance
understood rule as
I know and I never will.
The brutality, the sacrifice
It changes you.
Id rather be a good
man than a great King.
Is this my son I hear?
Or the woman he loves?
When you speak I never hear Mothers voice.
This is not for Jane, Father. She
does not know what I came here to say.
Now forbid me to see her or
say she can rule at my side,
it changes nothing.
- One son who wanted the Throne too much,
another who will not take it.
Is this my legacy?
- Loki died with honor.
I shall try to live the same.
Is that not legacy enough?
It belongs to you.
If you are worthy of it.
I shall try to be.
I cannot give you my blessing,
nor can I wish you good fortune.
I know.
If I were proud of the
man my son had become,
even that I could not say,
I would speak only from my heart:
Go, my son.
Thank you father.
No.
Thank you.
Subtitles by Bambula